Finding Aid for Charles F. Holman Papers 1973-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles F. Holman Papers 1973-1986
Holman, Charles F.
Detroit, Michigan, attorney and legal counselor; files reflecting his activity in the Michigan State NAACP
89356 Aa 2
1.3 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Mr. Charles F. Holman, III, (donor no. 7665 ) as a part of his personal papers related to the activity in the NAACP.
The collection is open for research.
Charles F. Holman, III, a Detroit, Michigan, attorney and legal counselor, is active in the areas of civil rights, elections, education of minorities, lobbying, and conflict of interest.
As a president of the University of Michigan NAACP College Chapter and as a member of the National Board of Directors of the NAACP, Mr. Holman was actively involved in the Michigan Youth and College Division of the NAACP. In his work he sought to secure better minority student representation at the university.
Mr. Holman's papers primarily reflect his activity in the Michigan State NAACP. The papers consist of 1.3 linear feet of material containing letters, memoranda, minutes, reports, and printed material documenting Holman's work in the state and national NAACP organizations.
The papers are organized in three series: Correspondence, arranged chronologically, 1973 and 1977-1986; NAACP Files, 1970-1986, arranged alphabetically; and Topical Files, 1978-1986, arranged alphabetically. Since the files are closely interrelated, the researcher is encouraged to review the files in all three series.
Subjects:
African Americans--Michigan.; Civil rights--Michigan.; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.
- Correspondence 1973, 1977-1986
  - 1973 (Box 1)
  - 1977 (Box 1)
  - 1978 (Box 1)
  - 1979 (Box 1)
  - 1981 (Box 1)
  - 1982 (Box 1)
  - 1983 (Box 1)
  - 1984 (Box 1)
  - 1985 (Box 1)
  - 1986 (Box 1)
- NAACP Files 1970-1986
  - Annual Legislative Conference Washington D.C. 1980 (Box 1)
  - Annual National Conventions 1974, 1977, 1979, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report of the Executive Director on the State of the NAACP 1983 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report 1985 (Box 1)
  - Budget 1978 (Box 1)
  - Budget 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Branch of the NAACP 1981-1983 (Box 1)
  - Legal Department
    - Annual Reports 1970-1976 (Box 1)
    - Memo to the National Board of the NAACP 1978 (Box 1)
  - Michigan State Conference of the NAACP Branches
    - Annual Convention 1982, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Resolutions 1981-1985 (Box 1)
    - Youth and College Division 1981-1986 (Box 1)
  - National Board of Directors
    - Letters, Memoranda 1973-1986 (Box 1)
    - Memoranda, Minutes, Reports 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - National Leadership Summit 1978 (Box 1)
  - National Youth Work Committee 1982-1986 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - NAACP News 1982 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Mobilizer 1981-1982 (Box 1)
    - Youth Line 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Policy Guide, Internal Affairs Memorandum 1983 (Box 1)
  - Special Contribution Fund
    - Letter 1978-1983 (Box 1)
    - Report on the Lecture and Discussion Tour of Four African Countries,... 1981 (Box 1)
  - Spingarm Medal Awards Committee 1981-1983 (Box 1)
  - Clippings 1981-1986, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Topical Files 1978-1986
  - Adams Case-Medical School 1986 (Box 2)
  - Allen's Summary Findings from a Preliminary Study of Black Students Adjustment 1981 (Box 2)
  - Black Action Movement of 1970 (chapter 2) circa 1982 (Box 2)
  - Department of Civil Rights 1978-1986 (Box 2)
  - Education and Schools Community Affairs 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Department of Education 1980-1985 (Box 2)
  - Michigan State Board of Education
    - Memoranda 1982 (Box 2)
    - Reports on Minorities 1980 (Box 2)
    - Reports on Minorities 1985-1986 (Box 2)
  - NAACP vs. Claiborne Hardware Co., Petition for Writ of Certiorari 1981 (Box 2)
  - Survey of Black Students 1980 (Box 2)
  - United States Youth Council 1983 (Box 2)
  - Washington's Case-Law School 1984 (Box 2)